Sullivan, The Honorable John J. collection, 1948-1983 Ms B40
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Sullivan, The Honorable John J. Collection, 1948-1983
1948-1987
Ms B40
Fairfield Museum and History Center
25.0 Linear feet (11,000 items)
This collection contains papers donated by Fairfield First Selectman John J. Sullivan. Half the collection is papers from various town departments and the other half is papers belonging to Sullivan.
Fairfield (Conn.: Town).
Fairfield (Conn.). First Selectman's Office.
Sullivan, John J., 1906-1997
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
John J. Sullivan (1906-1997) moved to Fairfield in 1936. He ran a flower shop until 1959 when he was elected First Selectman of Fairfield. He retained that office until 1983 when he chose not to stand for reelection. For further detail see Fairfield: The Biography of a Community 1639-1989 by Thomas J. Farnham, pp. 281-291.
Custodial History note
Boxes LV and LVI were donated by Mary Donahue and are from accession number L2011.7. Boxes LVII-LXI were donated by Robert Lee's son James and are from accession number L2010.31.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of 61 boxes and 1 oversize item. Boxes I through XXIX contain Fairfield town papers including sewer, conservation, real estate, financial, personnel, schools, CT Resources Recovery Authority and others. Boxes XXX through LIV are mainly papers involving John J. Sullivan. They have been placed in about the same order in which they were deposited. Boxes LV through LXI were later donations and contain papers relating to the running of the town of Fairfield as well as letters belonging to Sullivan and photographs. There are also letters between Sullivan and Selectman Robert Lee who is described as Sullivan's right arm. The oversize item is a resolution.
Custodial History note
These papers were deposited by John J. Sullivan.
Fairfield (Conn.: Town) .; Fairfield (Conn.: Town). Dept. of Aging .; Fairfield (Conn.: Town). Fairfield Community Development Advisory Committee .; Fairfield (Conn.: Town). Fairfield Conservation Dept. .; Connecticut Resources Recovery Authority; Fairfield(Conn.); Municipal bonds--Connecticut.; Municipal finance; Municipal officials and employees.; Old Post Road Association (Fairfield, Conn.); Real property--Valuation.; Schools--Connecticut.; Sewerage
- Box I: Sewer papers, 1972-1979; 206 items
- Box II: Sewer papers, 1980-1989; 200 items
- Box III: Sewer papers, 1980-1989; 200 items
- Box IV: Sewer papers, 1970-1989; 100 items
- Box V: Sewer papers, 1970-1989; 50 items
- Box VI: Conservation papers, 1970-1979; 20 items
- Box VII: Conservation papers, 1960-1989; 20 items
- Box VIII: Conservation papers, 1980-1989; 20 items
- Box IX: Town real estate papers, 1970-1989; 50 items
- Box X: Town real estate appraisal papers, 1960-1989; 25 items
- Box XI: Town real estate appraisal papers, 1960-1979; 150 items
- Box XII: Town real estate appraisal papers, 1960-1989; 20 items
- Box XIII: Town financial papers, Board of Finance, 1977-1984; 250 items
- Box XIV: Town financial papers, Board of Finance, 1980-1982; 250 items
- Box XV: Town financial papers, bond ratings and misc., 1970-1989; 150 items
- Box XVI: Town employee contracts, 1948-1988; 250 items
- Box XVII: Town personnel papers, 1960-1989; 200 items
- Box XVIII: Town personnel papers, 1970-1989; 200 items
- Box XIX: Town personnel papers, 1970-1989; 100 items
- Box XX: Town personnel papers, 1979-1989; 100 items
- Box XXI: Town school papers, 1970-1989; 250 items
- Box XXII: Town papers: special studies, charter, elderly, library alterations, community development program, federal aid, citizens community survey, 1970-1989; 75 items
- Box XXIII: Miscellaneous town papers, 1970-1989; 75 items
- Box XXIV: CT Resources Recovery Authority, 1970-1989; 25 items
- Box XXV: CT Resources Recovery Authority, 1970-1989; 75 items
- Box XXVI: CT Resources Recovery Authority, 1970-1989; 100 items
- Box XXVII: CT Resources Recovery Authority, 1970-1989; 25 items
- Box XXVIII: Publications (miscellaneous), 1960-1989; 20 items
- Box XXIX: Publications (miscellaneous), 1970-1989; 30 items
- Box XXX: Awards, certificates and congratulatory letters, 1960-1989; 50 items
- Box XXXI: Campaign and election papers, 1960-1989; 200 items
- Box XXXII: Speeches and miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 150 items
- Box XXXIII: Miscellaneous papers, 1968-1979; 100 items
- Box XXXIV: Miscellaneous papers, 1969-1989; 125 items
- Box XXXV: Miscellaneous papers, 1969-1970; 250 items
- Box XXVI: Miscellaneous papers, 1971-1972; 250 items
- Box XXVII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 1 of 5, file drawer #1, 1965-1977; 300 items
- Box XXXVIII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 1 of 5, file drawer #1, 1978-1980; 300 items
- Box XXXIX: Miscellaneous papers, Box 1 of 5, file drawer #1, 1981-1983; 300 items
- Box XL: Miscellaneous papers, Box 1 of 5, file drawer #1, 1960-1989; 300 items
- Box XLI: Miscellaneous papers, Box 2 of 5, file drawer #2, 1974-1975; 300 items
- Box XLII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 2 of 5, file drawer #2, 1973-1975; 300 items
- Box XLIII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 2 of 5, file drawer #2, 1972-1973; 300 items
- Box XLIV: Miscellaneous papers, Box 4 of 5, file drawer #3, 1960-1979; 250 items
- Box XLV: Miscellaneous papers, Box 4 of 5, file drawer #3, 1960-1989; 175 items
- Box XLVI: Miscellaneous papers, Box 4 of 5, file drawer #3, 1961; 100 items
- Box XLVII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 4 of 5, file drawer #3, 1962-1975; 200 items
- Box XLVIII: Miscellaneous papers, Box 4 of 5, file drawer #3, 1963-1965; 150 items
- Box XLIX: Miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 150 items
- Box L: Miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 125 items
- Box LI: Miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 150 items
- Box LII: Miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 125 items
- Box LIII: Miscellaneous papers, 1970-1989; 200 items
- Box LIV: Miscellaneous papers and photographs, 1960-1989; 150 items
- Box LV: Photographs and Miscellaneous, 1949-1999; 7 folders
  - Photographs, 1949-1950; Folder 1
  - Photographs; Oath of Office, 1960-1969; Folder 2
  - Photographs, 1970-1979; Folder 3
  - Photographs, 1980-1999; Folder 4
  - Coming to an End, 1983; Folder 5
  - Out of Office articles, 1980-1999; Folder 6
  - Southport Harbor Project, 1991; Folder 7
- Box LVI: Miscellaneous papers, 1914-1989; 9 folders
  - Letters and articles, 1960-1979; Folder 1
  - Penfield Reef Project, 1962; Folder 2
  - Papers and articles, 1970-1979; Folder 3
  - Letters and articles, 1980-1989; Folder 4
  - Independence Hall project and photographs, 1979; Folder 5
  - Country Club of Fairfield information, 1914-1966; Folder 6
  - Fairfield University commencement, autograph, Folder 7
  - Budget data, Folder 8
  - Campaign fliers and articles, Folder 9
- Box LVII: Miscellaneous papers, 1956-1963; 9 folders
  - Photographs, 1958, 1963; Folder 1
  - Campaign and election items, 1959; Folder 2
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961; Folder 3
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1963; Folder 4
  - Pine Creek, 1960-1963; Folder 5
  - Sewer, 1960-1963; Folder 6
  - Miscellaneous, 1956, 1959, 1961, 1962; Folder 7
  - Knights of Columbus by-laws, Folder 8
  - Knights of Columbus, Folder 9
- Box LVIII: Miscellaneous papers, 1964-1965; 8 folders
  - Budget-Board of Finance minutes, Folder 1
  - General, Folder 2
  - Letter to Bob Lee, Folder 3
  - Redevelopment (property rights), Folder 4
  - RTM Minutes, Folder 5
  - Old Post Road Association, Folder 6
  - RTM resolutions, Folder 7
  - Sewer, Folder 8
- Box LIX: Miscellaneous papers, 1966-1969; 11 folders
  - Re-election; photograph-Sullivan, Katona, Lee, Senator Dodd, 1966-1969; Folder 1
  - Campaign, 1966-1977; Folder 2
  - Letters and memos--Bob Lee to John Sullivan, 1966-1967; Folder 3
  - Charter revision-sewer, 1966-1967; Folder 4
  - Finance, 1966-1967; Folder 5
  - Judge Fitzpatrick, 1966-1967; Folder 6
  - General, 1966-1967; Folder 7
  - Pamphlets, 1966-1967; Folder 8
  - Processing procedures, 1966-1967; Folder 9
  - Selectman Robert Lee, 1966-1968; Folder 10
  - Sewer, 1967; Folder 11
- Box LX: Miscellaneous papers, 1973-1983; 8 folders
  - Election, 1973-1978; Folder 1A
  - Republican opponents, 1974-1975; Folder 1
  - Tribute to Sullivan; Voter list Districts 2-3, 1974-1975; Folder 2
  - Election, 1976-1977; Folder 3
  - Election/Corruption, 1976-1977; Folder 4
  - Campaign: conflict of interest/ethics, 1976-1977; Folder 5
  - General/Exxon, 1976-1977; Folder 6
  - Sullivan administration, 1982-1983; Folder 7
- Box LXI: Miscellaneous, 1959-1987; 7 folders
  - 5 Year Plans, 1959-1962; Folder 1
  - 5 Year Plans, 1966-1973; Folder 2
  - 5 Year Plans, 1975-1979; Folder 3
  - 5 Year Plans, 1980-1983; Folder 4
  - Town charter; personnel practices, Folder 5
  - 5 Year Forecasts, 1969-1987; Folder 6
  - Proposed historic district, 1976; Folder 7
- Oversize Item A: Resolution in honor of John J. Sullivan, 1989/24/10 (Oversize Manuscript Box 2)
  Separated Materials note
  Located in Oversize Manuscripts Box 2